Saraba chikyuu yo, ai suru hito yo
Farewell Earth, and to the ones we love
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
Yamato
Space Battleship
Soldiers of Love
Chikyuu wo sukuu shimei o obite tatakau otoko
Men fight on a mission to save Earth
Moeru roman
It's a burning passion
Dareka ga kore wo yaraneba naranu
Someone has to do this
Kitai no hito ga ore tachi naraba
We are the trusted ones
Ginga wo hanare Iscandar e harubaru nozomu
Leaving the Milky Way to go all the way to Iscandar
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
Warp complete.
All departments, hurry cross-checks.
Andromeda's primary engine is stable.
Interior environment nominal.
Wave motion engine failed to restart.
Possible critical damage to the core.
Canceling trans-warp interlock
and releasing the gravity anchor.
Multiple large ships sighted straight ahead.
They're Andromeda-class early mass production ships.
They'll join the Garmillas fleet at
Mars to form the final defense line.
Inform HQ...
...this ship will head to the Time
Fault facility for emergency repair.
Aye, sir.
I'll save the Yamato no matter what.
Who are you ?
You must be with the United Forces.
I...
Where am I ?
Are you...?
Why...?
Why ?
During the fight with Domel's fleet, the Yamato was infiltrated by their special forces...
...resulting in Chief Operations
Officer Mori being taken as a hostage.
I ordered Lt Kodai to rescue
Chief Operations Officer Mori.
Kodai succeeded on his mission
and returned to the ship with Mori.
After the rescue operation, the Yamato left
the Garmillas sector, and headed to Iscandar.
To all crewmen of the Yamato, this is Captain Okita.
We've finally reached Iscandar.
Look, Iscandar is right before your eyes.
I want to take this opportunity to...
Then, Yuki's memories won't come back ?
No, they actually did.
She recalled the memories she
had lost because of the accident.
But she lost the memories of the last 4 years ?
About the Yamato, the journey to Iscandar...
...and about Chief Tactical Officer Kodai ?
Maybe it's temporary.
Something might trigger...
The possibility is near zero.
That's Dr. Sado's opinion.
Just focus on your task.
Hey, you...
We have lots of company today.
Their language has been analyzed.
They're worthy of receiving Zemuria's knowledge.
Let's borrow that guy.
Who is this ?
That's not a slate.
It's like a screen.
Those are Gatlantian letters.
Gatlantians are man-made soldiers...
...with only a sense of loyalty and hostility.
Farm animals with a
humanoid body and green skin.
Analyzer ?
What's wrong ?
Gatlantians are ideal pawns in war.
So that Zemurians don't get hurt.
Zemuria...?
Sounds like the name of this planet.
This place appears to be Zemuria's memory bank.
The Gatlantians were created on this planet.
But the Zemurians broke a taboo.
Type Zorder...
1,000 Years Ago
...the most advanced model with a
network capable of using telepathic waves.
It has a complex mental structure, massive
memory capability, and is also capable of spy operations.
He exceeds normal Gatlantians.
He's almost...
...human.
Why ?
Why doesn't it awaken ?
Why doesn't it accept me ?
The Ark of Destruction comes to life only
when humans are deemed an evil species.
It's left for humans to decide.
No matter how closely we are engineered
to be like humans, we're still artificial.
We can't judge humans.
We can, exactly because of that.
We're incapable of reproduction.
We have no love or ego.
We're the most pure intelligent life form.
Humans created a new kind of human
to free themselves from their fate.
Are you going to raise the dead ?
The Ark of Creation is paired
with the Ark of Destruction.
If it can only hear the voice of a human, I'll sacrifice the woman I love the most...
...so she can be the judge who delivers justice to humans.
He was struck by bad
karma for breaking a taboo .
A farm animal which can think
like a human can't remain an animal.
Zorder carried out a revolt, then a war
between Gatlantis and humans began.
How is it ?
No use. We have to get back to the
Yamato and hook this up to the main host.
Requesting a connection to the main host.
This unit can't hold our knowledge.
Hey, you two...
We're storytellers of Zemuria.
Our duty is to transfer the history of the planet to an entity with worthy intelligence and memory capacity.
We're inadequate ?
They took over Analyzer easily.
We can't take it to the Yamato.
But we need information,
including the exact location of this planet.
Zemuria's current coordinates are unknown to us.
What do you mean ?
It's because of the witch.
A human traitor helped the Gatlanians revolt.
The witch sided with Zorder and hid Zemuria in a mist.
A witch ?
Let's take this to the Yamato.
Sifar Sabera...
Do you hear my voice ?
We don't have much time.
Replicated cells disintegrate quickly.
Remember what humans
did to you, a fellow human...
...and what they took from us.
Deliver justice for your rage, sadness, and despair.
Let's end our suffering.
Humans rob and kill because of love.
Let's end the pain of living on...
...through the salvation called extinction.
No...
This battle will determine the fate of the
entire human race throughout the universe.
Together, we must defend the
Earth sector for the honor of Garmillas.
This battle will decide the rise or fall of mankind.
This isn't the time for political beliefs, so I'll help.
But can we really win ?
Ichinose, your control was too slow.
Aye, sir.
The use of the trim lever during
a maneuver must be within 0.20.
Yes, sir.
0.20...?
I wish I could replace these useless hands.
Replace ?
I've heard the production of some high performance prosthetic arms has begun in the Time Fault.
They're meant for the injured, but if I volunteer...
Survey the Gatlantis gravitational field fluctuation,
and then adjust the approach limit.
It's your seat, Mori.
Sorry, I...
I'm sure you will...
That's Captain Okita Juzo.
I know the name.
He died on this ship during a battle.
What are you expecting ?
I didn't ask you to save me.
If I had died there...
You want my favor for saving me...
I've been wondering for a while.
Gatlantians deny and mock love.
That may be proof of knowing what love is.
They might hate love because of pain and suffering.
The Yamato's landed on a planet called Zemuria.
You know this...
...and the fact that it was the home
planet of Gatlantis, don't you ?
It was once a beautiful planet,
lush and green, just like Earth.
That was more than 1,000 years ago.
And you are...
...the last human of Zemuria...
Even though you are a copy of a traitor, you're a pure entity with genuine Zemurian blood.
We grant you, the last human of Zemuria, the
whole record of the planet we've been protecting.
Unlike you humans we Gatlantians
have no ability to reproduce.
However, he will become me.
He is my future.
"Gatlantis is not bound by love. Therefore, they can build a fair and peaceful society."
That was Zorder's claim, but he
himself, couldn't free himself from love.
The King of Gatlantis has a wife and child ?
The female traitor played mother to a clone baby, huh ?
If you want to save this woman and the child, tell us where your army's going to gather.
It was a shameful act.
But the Zemurians were desperate.
Having his loved ones taken
hostage, Zorder made a choice.
A choice ?
Zorder's choice was futile.
Using Zorder's information, the Zemurians
quelled the Gatlantian revolt quickly.
They eventually turned against Zorder,
and broke their promise.
His wife and his child were...
Despite everything, he survived.
He left Zemuria with the surviving Gatlantians.
That wasn't the end. He had an objective...
...an objective to revive the Ark of Destruction,
a legacy of ancient Archelious...
...which is believed to lie at the edge
of empty space with no star in sight.
No...
Why ?!
This darkness is like the inside of your heart.
Instead of destroying the universe,
your frozen heart needs to be broken free.
Sabera...
Please give up this path you're on.
The judgment is made.
This is the end of the quest
of more than 100 years.
We must accept...
No.
We have the data. Make a copy of
Sabera with her memories intact.
If she can control the
Ark of Destruction, that will be enough.
If you encounter any problems, try again.
We can make as many copies as we want.
Humans are incomplete in the first place.
Their pitiful lives are cursed with love.
Zemuria was doomed, and it was
shrouded in an ominous white gas.
As long as humans act like humans,
they can't break free from the sin of loving.
Who created such a thing ?
Who proliferated it throughout the universe ?
The ancient Archelious experiment ended in failure.
An evil breed must be terminated.
Then we will wait for the birth of a new breed.
A new intelligent life form which can bring true order and stability to this universe.
The Comet Empire's megalopolis is
built around the Ark of Destruction.
It's the embodiment of true love,
which can burn away all pain.
Sabera.
The anti-warp field has disappeared.
Gravitational incline near Gatlantis, intensifying.
A.I. prediction matches B-7.
The White Comet has begun to move.
Finally...
All ships, maintain distance
from the critical escape line !
Gravitational wave, incoming.
Contact the Mars Defense Force !
The Comet Empire is leaving the Jupiter sector, and is expected to warp into the Mars sector !
Stay on alert !
Episode 20
Gatlantis, the Cursed Children
Kodai Susumu:
Mori Yuki:
Shima Daisuke:
Analyzer:
Saijo Miki:
Katsuragi Touko:
Saito Hajime:
Nagakura Shiori:
Ono Daisuke
Kuwashima Houko
Suzumura Kenichi
Cho
Moriya Satomi
Kaida Yuko
Tochi Hiroki
Amagai Kazusa
Todo Saki:
Kanzaki Megumi
Ichinose Mina:
Yamanami Osamu:
Okita Juzo:
Takagaki Ayahi
Hayashibara Megumi
Kurosawa Tomoyo
Ebara Masashi
Sugo Takayuki
Cottony clouds drift high across the sky
Sora takaku nagareru kieyuku wata no kumo
Klaus Keyman:
Loren Barrel:
Fomt Burger:
Zorder:
Gailane:
Sabera:
Andromeda XO:
Andromeda Comm Officer:
Andromeda Nav Officer:
Storyteller A:
Storyteller B:
Kamiya Hiroshi
Terasoma Masaki
Suwabe Junichi
Tezuka Hideaki
Shibata Hidekatsu
Kaida Yuko
Ichinose Hiroaki
Fujimura Kento
Yano Masaaki
Ikeshita Ririko
Matsumoto Yuki
Holding out both hands, I stretch out in the falling leaves
Ryoote wo age ah senobi shita rakuyou
As the house lights come on, I wish to meet people smiling at each other
Akari tomoru mado waraiau hito ni aitai to omou
Believing in a miraculous enounter to become real, I shout out for love
Sou kanau hazusa kiseki no deai ni ai sakenda
Luminous lives meet and bond with each other
Kagayaku jinsei no meguriawase tsumuideyuku
Let’s keep on living our lives
Bokura no jinsei wo tayumazu ni susumi tsuzukeyou
Let’s begin the story of our lives
Bokura no jinsei no monogatari wo saa hajimeyou
Preview
It sings the song of destruction.
It's called Golem.
Where is it now ?
The killing will never end.
This is our ship, a human one.
Raise the hull !
Episode 21
Escape from Nightmare !!